Guide to the Kenneth G. Wilson papers, 1960-2000.
Wilson, Kenneth G. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Kenneth G. Wilson papers, 1960-2000.
14-22-4086
Wilson, Kenneth G.(Kenneth Geddes),
6.3 cubic feet.
Correspondence, manuscripts, publications, research materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional papers of Kenneth G. Wilson.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Kenneth G. Wilson taught at Cornell from 1963 to 1987. In 1987, Wilson left Cornell for Ohio State University where he helped found the Physics Education Research Group, and focused on physics and science education. Wilson won the Nobel Prize in Physics in 1982.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional papers of Kenneth G. Wilson. Collection includes publications and notes for publications by Wilson, correspondence, material relating to Wilson's teaching and courses, data, computer printouts, and research notebooks. Items relate to his own work in particle physics, quantum field theory, supercomputing and the Cornell Theory Center, and education reform.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Wilson, Kenneth G. 1936-2013.
Subjects:
Atomic physics.; Educational change.; Physics -- Study and teaching.; Physics -- Study and teaching; Quantum field theory.; Renormalization group.; Supercomputers
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Selected Materials from Cornell
Box 1
Series II. Wilson's Publications
Box 1, 2, 3
Series III. Correspondence and Memorabilia, Materials from Wilson's Physics Courses
Box 3
Series IV. Wilson's Research Notebooks from Cornell
Box 4
Series V. Raw Research Notes
Box 6, 7
Series VI. Computer Output
Box 5
Series VII. Materials on Supercomputing and the Cornell Supercomputing Theory Center
Box 6
Series VIII. Materials on Education Reform
Box 7
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Selected Materials from Cornell
  Material selected by Ken to take with him to the Dibner Institute for the History of Science and Technology (visited 2002)
  - Gibbs' Lecture "Proof of a Conjecture by Dyson", CV, 1962-2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Abstract of Gibbs Lecture, American Mathematical Society, 1980 reprint of early paper "Proof of a Conjecture by Dyson", several versions of Wilson's CV
  - "Generalized Wannier Functions","Future of Supercomputing", c. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Manuscript and proof of "Generalized Wannier Functions" with notes, letter from Michael Teter (Corning Glass Laboratory) rough notes on "Future of Supercomputing"
  - Monte Carlo Renormalization Group on FPS Supercomputer, c. 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Red folder: Implementation of Monte Carlo Renormalization Group transformations on the Floating Point Systems supercomputer
  - Research notes on atomic physics, strong coupling lattice gauge theory (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes on atomic physics calculations, Floating Point systems implementation, rough notes for "Future of Supercomputing", Indian exercise book (Balarpur Industries) filled with strong coupling lattice gauge theory calculations (of vacuum energy?)
  - Notes on quantum chemistry and supercomputing (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes on programming Pade approximants, notes on P, C, and T (for a class?), manuscript on quantum chemistry, press release on supercomputing
  - Lecture and reference notes, c.1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Quantization of the electromagnetic field, some QFT cross section formulae, notes on Johnson's paper on the Thirring model, 4-pt functions in the Thirring model, conformal group, generators of the Lorentz group, solution of the Ising model, high-temperature series calculations (Ising model?), correlation functions in the Ising model, "Schwinger methods" (correlation functions) in the Ising model, notes on Toeplitz determinants (for the Ising model), thermodynamics of a monatomic gas, logarithmic integrals, integrals over lattice momenta, lattice quantum field theory calculations, Gaussian integration, motion of a particle in slowly varying fields,
  - Manuscripts of Unpublished Papers, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    A Model for Coupling Constant Renormalization LNS-65-13 (1965) (7 pp), Renormalization Theory for Strong Interactions (1968-9?), about 100 pages of manuscript, perhaps to accompany "Nonlagrangian Models …" Also original manuscripts for the materials "selected for the Dibner Institute 2004"
  - Rough notes on supercomputing, blockspin, instantons, atomic physics, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Rough notes on supercomputing, rough notes on block spin calculations and computer implementation, exchange of letters with Paulo Caldas, unpublished manuscript on instantons in lattice gauge theory, rough notes on atomic density matrix computations, rough notes on supercomputer revolution
  - Rough notes on Wannier function, blockspin, FPS programing, 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Rough notes on Wannier function calculations, notes on Dirac equation on a lattice, notes on block spin formalism, rough notes on Floating Point Systems programming, synchrotrons, very rough notes on atomic calculations, Cornell Theory Center, computing revolution, Ising simulations
  - Research notes on atomic physics, fixed source problem, 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Rough notes on atomic physics calculations (1970's), very rough notes for FPS programming, few pages of manuscript on operator products (1964?), notes on "topological anaysis" -- convergence of operator interation in a renormalization group transformation in the fixed source problem, notes on analysis of the fixed source problem
  - Notes on topics in quantum field theory, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Effective Hamiltonian in the fixed source problem, relation between scattering cross sections and the S-matrix, representations of the Lorentz group, Lorentz-invariant wave equations, relation between scattering cross sections and the S-matrix (version 2), chiral SU(3)xSU(3) symmetry, some current algebra formulae, representations of SU(3), Dirac equation in 1 dimension, Lorentz group commutators, 2nd order weak interactions (with Operator Product Expansion), Steinberger calculation of pi-zero decay, irreducible representations of the Lorentz group, also: manuscript for "Regge Roles and Multiple Production" (1963) (+loose notes on renormalization group transformations)
  - Notes for Physics 574 - Applications of Quantum Mechanics, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Looseleaf notebook w. problem sets and course notes (notes after the green separator might be by Tung-Mow Yan), after the green separator, quotes from Ken taken down by students: e.g. "If you do the calculation properly and come back a year later, you will find that it is still divergent…"
- Series II. Wilson's Publications
  Arranged chronologically. Mainly, these are reprints, but in some cases, a manuscript or other correspondence is included. These cases are noted.
  - Dispersion Relations for Infinite Plasmas, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Manuscript from Wilson's graduate study at Caltech
  - An Investigation of the Low Equation and the Chew-Mandelstam Equations, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Ph.D Thesis, Manuscript
  - Regge Poles and Multiple Production, Acta Phys. Aust. 17, 37, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Manuscript located within Series I.
  - Proof of a Conjecture by Dyson, J. Math. Phys. 3, 1040, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    With a related news article from Science (2005)
  - A Set of Double Integral Equations for Low-Energy Pion-Pion Scattering, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Manuscript from Harvard "to be submitted to Phys. Rev." (but apparently not submitted)
  - Solution of the Symmetric Scalar Low Equation in the One Meson Approximation, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Manuscript from Cornell
  - A Model for Coupling Constant Renormalization, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    LNS-65-13; this unpublished manuscript is located in Series I
  - On Products of Quantum Field Operators at Short Distances, 1965, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Manuscript submitted to the Physical Review (1965) (and parts of an earlier draft), referee report (from Arthur Wightman), notes for an answer to the referee report the paper was never resubmitted. Wilson developed these ideas for many more years and announced them in his article "Nonlagrangian Models of Current Algebra" (1969)
  - Renormalization Theory for Strong Interactions, c. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Unpublished manuscript located in Series I
  - Some Experiments on Multiple Production, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    CLNS-131; eventually published in the proceedings of the 1973 Scottish Universities Summer School
  - Renormalization Group and Strong Interactions, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Phys. Rev. D 3, 1818
  - Renormalization Group and Critical Phenomena I. Renormalization Group and the Kadanoff Scaling Picture, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Phys. Rev. B 4, 3174
  - Renormalization Group and Critical Phenomena II. Phase-Space Cell Analysis of Critical Behavior, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Phys. Rev. B 4, 3184
  - Deep Inelastic Scattering - Theory, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Draft of the article for the proceedings of the 5th International Symposium on Electron and Photon Interactions at High Energies, Cornell
  - Gauge Transformations in the Thirring Model, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Phys. Rev. D 5, 1026
  - Renormalization Group II (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Unpublished lectures given at Cornell, lecture notes by J. Serene
  - Renormalization Group III (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Breakdown of Landau Theory, Fluctuations and Renormalization (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Offprint from the 1973 Nobel symposium proceedings containing an abstract of the talk and a record of the discussion
  - Solution of the Spin-1/2 Kondo Hamiltonian, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Offprint from the 1973 Nobel symposium
  - Quantum Field Theory Models in Less Than 4 Dimensions, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Phys. Rev. D 7, 2911
  - The Renormalization Group and the Epsilon Expansion, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Phys. Reports 12C
  - Confinement of Quarks, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Phys. Rev. D 10, 2445
  - Finite Lattice Approximation to Renormalization Groups, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Phys. Rev. B 11, 3431
  - Temperature-Dependent Susceptibility of the Symmetric Anderson Model: Connection to the Kondo Model, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Phys. Rev. Lett. 35, 1101
  - Renormalization Group Methods, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Adv. Math. 16, 170
  - The Renormalization Group and Block Spins, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Boltzmann Medal Address
  - The Renormalization Group: Critical Phenomena and the Kondo Problem, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Rev. Mod. Phys 47, 773; with a folder of original artwork for this and contemporaneous papers
  - Quark Confinement and Lattice Calculations, c. 1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Preprint of a talk that seems to honor Paul Dirac
  - The Renormalization Group - Introduction, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Published in Phase Transitions and Critical Phenomena, v. 6, ed. by Domb and Green
  - Relativistically Invariant Lattice Theories, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Published in the Proceeding of the 1976 Coral Gables Conference
  - Quantum Chromodynamics on a Lattice, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Preprint of Cargese Summer School lecture notes
  - Susceptibility of the Asymmetric Anderson Model: Relevance to Valence Fluctuation Compounds, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Preprint, published in Valence Instabilities and Related Narrow-Band Phenomena, Parks, ed.
  - Problems in Physics with Many Scales of Length, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Scientific American 241, 158; with page of notes (small corrections) and reprint of the Polish translation
  - Monte Carlo Calculations for the Lattice Gauge Theory, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Cornell preprint CLNS/80/442
  - Renormalization Group Approach to the Anderson Model of Dilute Magnetic Alloys. I. Static properties for the symmetric case, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Phys. Rev. B 21, 1003
  - Renormalization Group Approach to the Anderson Model of Dilute Magnetic Alloys. II. Static properties for the asymmetric case, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Phys. Rev. B 21, 1044
  - Experiences with a Floating Point Systems Array Processor, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Cornell preprint CLNS/81/477; "to be published in the series in Computational Physics on Parallel Computation"
  - Monte Carlo Techniques in Code Optimization, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Preprint, published in ACM SIGMICRO newsletter 13, 143
  - A Remnant of Chiral Symmetry on the Lattice, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Phys. Rev. D 25, 2649; with a manuscript page and some correspondence
  - The Renormalization Group and Critical Phenomena, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Rev. Mod. Phys. 55, 583; Nobel Prize address (1982), reprinted with the autobiographical sketch from the Nobel Foundation's publication associated correspondence is included
  - Quelle Informatique pour la Science?, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    La Recherche 14, 1004; magazine article in French, followed by commentary by Y. Pomeau and N. Sourlas
  - Science, Industry, and the New Japanese Challenge, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Proc. of the IEEE 72, 6
  - Monte Carlo Renormalization-Group Calculations of Critical Behavior in the Simple-Cubic Ising Model, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Phys. Rev. B 29, 4030
  - Monte Carlo Renormalization Group and the Three-Dimensional Ising Model, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Preprint of lectures given at the 1983 NATO Advanced Study Institute, Cargese with handwritten manuscript
  - Langevin Simulation of Lattice Field Theories, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Phys. Rev. D 32, 2736
  - Renormalization Group Approach for Electronic Structure, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Phys. Rev. Lett. 56, 412; with draft and referee reports
  - Optimized Trial Wave Functions for Quantum Monte Carlo Calculations, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Phys. Rev. Lett 60, 1719
  - Fourier Acceleration in Lattice Gauge Theories. I. Landau Gauge Fixing, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Phys. Rev. D 37, 1581
  - Fourier Acceleration in Lattice Gauge Theories. III. Updating Field Configurations, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Phys. Rev. D 41, 1953
  - Grand Challenges to Computational Science, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Future Generation Computer Systems 5, 171; with correspondence
  - Generalized Wannier Functions, 1987, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Cornell Theory Center preprint, submitted to J. Computational Physics, 1987, submitted to Phys. Rev. B 1989, not published
  - Ab Initio Quantum Chemistry: A Source of Ideas for Lattice Gauge Theorists, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Published in proceedings of Lattice 89, Nucl. Phys. B (Proc. Suppl.) 17, 82; with preprint distribution list
  - Light-Front Tamm Dancoff Field Theory, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Phys. Rev. Lett. 65, 2959
  - Towards a Solution of Quantum Chromodynamics on the Light-Front, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Ohio State Unversity preprint
  - Perturbative Renormalization of Null-Plane QED, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Phys. Rev. D 43, 3411
  - Basis Set Reduction in Hilbert Space, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Phys. Rev. Lett. 69, 800
  - Perturbative Renormalizability wiht an Infinite Number of Relevant and Marginal Operators, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Nucl. Phys. B 403, 587
  - On the Relativistic Bound State Problem in Light-Front Yukawa Model, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Draft of a paper
  - Light-Front Tamm-Dancoff Method: Hydrogen Atom and Positronium, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Preprint published in the proceedings of the 1992 Kazimierz summer school
  - Light-Front Tamm-Dancoff Method: Hydrogen Atom and 2D Yukawa Model, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Preprint published in the proceedings of the 1992 Paris conference on QCD vacuum structure
  - Positronia in Light-Front Tamm-Dancoff QED, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Ohio State University report DOE/ER/HUEAP-009; preliminary version (never completed?)
  - Renormalization of Overlapping Transverse Divergences in a Model Light-Front Hamiltonian w/ Glazek, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Phys. Rev. D 47, 4657; reprints and preprint versions, correspondence with the referee
  - Similarity Transformation for Renormalization of Light-Front Hamiltonians w/ Glazek, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Draft, never completed?
  - Renormalization of Hamiltonians w/ Glazek, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Warsaw preprint IFT/6/93 submitted to Phys. Rev. D, never published? with some correspondence
  - Mass Renormalization in Light-Front Tamm-Dancoff QED, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Phys. Rev. D 48, 4856; various preprint versions and correspondence
  - The Efficient Treatment of High Excitations in CI Calculations, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Chem. Phys. Lett 231, 263; reprint and Ohio State University preprint
  - Nonperturbative QCD: A Weak-Coupling Treatment on the Light Front, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Phys. Rev. D 49, 6720
  - Quarkonia in Hamiltonian Light-Front QCD, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    Phys. Rev. Lett. 78, 1227
  - Renormalization Group for Hamiltonians, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    Preprint and publication in the proceedings of the 9th physics summer school on Computational Physics, Canberra
  - Object-Oriented Techniques in Large Scientific Computing Projects, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Computers in Physics 11, 467
  - Science as a Cultural Construct, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Nature 386, 545; draft manuscript
  - Asymptotic Freedom and Bound States in Hamiltonian Dynamics, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Phys. Rev. D 57, 3558
  - Limit Cycles in Quantum Theories, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Phys. Rev. Lett. 89, 230401; eprint version
  - Wiley Handbook of Molecular Physics and Quantum Chemistry, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    Forward to volume 1; numerous drafts and correspondence concerning them
  - "Universality, Marginal Operators, and Limit Cycles" (with Glazek), 2004 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Phys. Rev. B 69, 094304
  - The Origins of Lattice Gauge Theory, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    Published in the proceedings of Lattice 2004 Nucl. Phys. B (Proc. Suppl.) 140, 3 (2005) reprints, manuscript with corrections, slide from the lecture, associated correspondence
  - Precise Numerical Results for Limit Cycles in the Quantum Three-Body Problem, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Phys. 321, 225; reprints and preprint, and a draft version
  - Miscellaneous Technical Articles (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Includes an article on Gaussian basis sets for atomic physics, the draft of a grant proposal for the Cornell Theory Center, an article on constituent quarks, section 1 -- Critical Phenomena (draft from a post-1983 paper) and other miscellaneous materials
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence with Publishers (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Correspondence with Physical Review, World Scientific
  - Slides from Wilson's Talks (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - PhD Thesis Draft (Steven White?) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series III. Correspondence and Memorabilia, Materials from Wilson's Physics Courses
  - Letters of recommendation and replies to requests for evaluation, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence on history and philosophy of science, 1991-2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Handwritten draft "Psychological Paradigms and Scientific Truth"
  - Correspondence with politicians about science, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Includes Congressional testimony
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1985-2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Mostly replies to invitations
  - Materials related to grant proposals at Cornell and Ohio State, 1986-1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Materials specifically concerning the Cornell Theory Center are in Box # 8, folder #5
  - Various papers sent to Wilson for comments, 1978-1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Includes two sub-folders: "Awards Won by Ken - Correspondence" and "Awards Won by Ken - Information"
  - Materials related to Wilson's awards, 1977-2005 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Materials related to Wilson's Nobel Prize award, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Interviews at Roundtables, 1985-2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Transcript of a roundtable on supercomputing, 1985, interview at Ohio State University, 2000, videotape of American Physical Society luncheon with Nobel laureates: "Celebrate a Century of Physics, Nobel Luncheon Version", 1999 (V-7155)
  - In memory of E. Bright Wilson, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ken Wilson vs. Columbia State University, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Correspondence regarding a fraudulent university using Wilson's name
  - Lecture Notes: Quantum Mechanics (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Previously stored in a binder
  - Lecture Notes: Quantum Field Theory, c. 1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous materials from Wilson's courses at Cornell (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Includes lecture notes, problem sets
- Series IV. Wilson's Research Notebooks from Cornell, 1980s
  Mainly computer-related; includes 22 green notebooks, documentation of "Basis Set Reduction" by Wilson and Wenzel
  - 2-D Ising Calculations (Box 4)
    Notebook; Monte Carlo and comparison to high temperature series
  - Schroedinger Equation (Box 4)
    Notebook; numerical methods for solution
  - SU(3) Gauge Theory with Fermions (Box 4)
    Notebook; formalism for Monte Carlo implementation
  - APPEAL (Box 4)
    Notebook; design of an assembler language
  - CMS Operations (Box 4)
    Notebook; various terminal command line instructions
  - 1972 Graduate Students (Box 4)
    Notebook
  - Optimizer, 1982 (Box 4)
    Notebook; seems to be for paper on Code Optimization
  - Untitled (Box 4)
    Notebook; timing tests on lattice gauge theory loop expectation value evaluations
  - UCSD Pascal (Box 4)
    Notebook; vector operations in this language
  - Computer Committee (Box 4)
    Notebook; discussion of prices, strategy, also many pages of lattice gauge theory calculation
  - Lattice Gauge Theory Coordinate Space Program (Box 4)
  - APTRAN Testing (Box 4)
  - 370 to AP Conversion (Box 4)
  - Quark Lattice Program (Box 4)
    Notebook; computer program for strong coupling calculations
  - Quark Lattice Program, Book 2 (Box 4)
  - Untitled (Box 4)
    Notebook; notes on formalism for block spins and gauge fixing
  - APTRAN (Box 4)
    Notebook; computer operation sequencing
  - Lattice Gauge Theory Free Quark Fixed Point (Box 4)
    Notebook; attempt to find this numerically
  - Lattice Gauge Theory Monte Carlo (Box 4)
  - Lattice Gauge Theory Free Quark Limit for Monte Carlo Formulation (Box 4)
  - SO(3) Extension of MCRG Lattice Gauge Program (Box 4)
    Notebook; some formalism, mostly program structure
  - AP Routines (Box 4)
  - Basis Set Reduction, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Previously stored in binder; by K.G. Wilson and W. Wenzel, computer program description
  - Documentation of the Basis Set Reduction Program (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Notes Accompanying Basis Set Reduction (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Series V. Raw Research Notes
  Mainly from Ohio State; grouped as they were in the original boxes
  - Notes from Cornell (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Mainly on computer implementations for light-front QCD
  - Raw Notes-Mainly Atomic Physics Calculations (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Raw Notes-Mainly Light-Front Hamiltonian Calculations (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Ohio State Note Pads-Mainly Light-Front Hamiltonian (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Notes from Ohio State-Mainly Light-Front QCD (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Raw Notes-Mainly Science Education (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Series VI. Computer Output, 1981-1985 (Box 5)
  Miscellaneous Computer Output from Cornell; includes report: "Simulating QCD with Dynamical Wilson and Staggered Fermions"
- Series VII. Materials on Supercomputing and the Cornell Supercomputing Theory Center
  Includes documentation for the Gibbs Project
  - Articles on Supercomputing, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    "Theoretical Science and the Future of Large Scale Computing," "CERN Courier" (1983) manuscript, "Computing Support for Scientific Research," "Technology and Science of Informatics" (1983) page proofs and manuscript with corrections
  - Drafts for Articles on Supercomputing, c. 1983 (Box 6, Folder 2)